Brent P. Woo

bwoo@uw.edu

Linguistics Ph.D. Student at University of Washington, Seattle Updated: Sept. 16, 2016

Summary

Research	Syntax (coordination, coordinate ellipsis phenomena, idioms), Slavic languages, experimental methods
Academic	Taught standalone Advanced Undergraduate Syntax class, TA'd for 3 quarters.
	Presented original research at international workshop (Brussels) and LSA.
Service	Public Scholarship I've worked at both the LINGUIST List and the Linguistic
	Society of America (LSA) and continue to serve as the elected LSA Program
	Committee student member.

Education

2018 (exp.)	University of Washington, Seattle Ph.D. Linguistics
2013	Eastern Michigan University M.A. Linguistics
2011	University of California, Los Angeles B.A. Linguistics B.A. Russian Studies Cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa
Sum 2015	Prešov University. Prešov, Slovakia. Studium Carpato-Ruthenorum Summer School for Rusyn Language
Sum 2012	California State University, Long Beach CSU Strategic Language and Culture Certificate (SLCC): Russian
Sum 2009	Russian State University for the Humanities. Moscow, Russia. Russian study abroad, via CSU Northridge SLI Program

Awards and Grants

2016	LCUGA Best Student Abstract Award and Travel Grant.
2016	Slavic Excellence Prize, Graduate. UW Department of Slavic Languages.
2015-16	UW Foreign Language and Area Studies (FLAS) Graduate Year Fellowship: Finnish (\$33,000)
2015	Conference Travel Grant, University of Washington Graduate School
2015	Conference Travel Grant, University of Washington Department of Linguistics
2013	EMU Distinguished Graduate Student in Linguistics
2013,2012	Conference Travel Grant, Eastern Michigan University Graduate School
2013	Phi Beta Kappa, UCLA.
2011	UCLA Foreign Language and Area Studies (FLAS) Undergraduate Year Fellowship: Croatian (\$15,000)
2010	UCLA Russian Student of the Year
2009	Strategic Language Initiative Fellowship Full tuition support and stipend for summer language program in Moscow

Conference Activity

Peer-reviewed presentations

(2017)	The unification of conjunction and disjunction: the case of and/or. [poster] Linguistic Society of America 91st Annual Meeting. (LSA 2017) Austin, Texas.
(2016)	Slash: A New Coordinator in English and its Behavior Slash Structure Linguistics Conference at UGA 3 (LCUGA 3), Theme: the lexicon University of Georgia. Athens, Georgia. [Best Student Abstract award, Travel award]
2015	Breaking idioms with right node raising Brussels Conference on Generative Linguistics 8: The Grammar of Idioms KU Leuven, Brussels, Belgium.
2013	Zero Copula in Russian Graduate Research Fair Eastern Michigan University. Ypsilanti, MI.
2012	Cyrillic Graphization of Dungan Graduate Research Fair Eastern Michigan University. Ypsilanti, MI.
2012	LL-MAP: Three interns' journey with language and technology [poster] Linguistic Society of America 86th Annual Meeting Portland, OR.

Conferences Organized

2016	April 22-24. Northwest Linguistics Conference (NWLC)
2014-2015	Arranged 15 invited speakers for UW Linguistics department colloquium series,
	through the Ac. Year.
2011	April 9, 2011. Southern California Undergraduate Linguistics Conference
	(SCULC) at UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.
2010	April 2010. Southern California Undergraduate Linguistics Conference (SCULC)
	at UCLA, Los Angeles, CA.

Teaching Experience

Spr 2017	Introduction to Linguistic Thought (TA)
Aut 2016	Survey of Linguistic Methods and Theories (Instructor)
Sum 2016	Syntax II: Advanced Undergraduate X-bar Syntax (Instructor)
Sum 2015	Syntax II: Advanced Undergraduate X-bar Syntax (Instructor)
Spr 2015	Introduction to Language and Society (TA)
Win 2015	Fundamentals of Grammar (TA)
Aut 2014	Fundamentals of Grammar (TA)
2016	Private tutor in Beginning Russian language

Guest Lectures

2016	February 17 2016. "Semantic classes of verbs". LING 100.
2015	May 4 2015. "Style shifting". LING 233.
2015	March 13 2015. "Syntax of PP". LING 100.
2014	December 3 2014. "Complements in VPs". LING 100.

Pedagogy

2016	Sept 22-23. Facilitator for workshop "Dealing with Cheating and Plagiarism".
	UW Linguistics Department TA training.
2016	Sept 19-20. Facilitator for workshops "Teaching Quiz Sections in the Social
	Sciences and Humanities: First Day and Beyond". TA/RA Conference on
	Teaching, Learning, and Research.
2015	Autumn 2015. "CLUE" Tutor for LING 100. Evening tutoring sessions and exam
	review.

Service to Profession

(forthcoming) Review. Languages in the world. *LINGUIST List*.

Community Involvement and Outreach

2016	September 3. "Languages of the World". University Beyond Bars, Public Lecture series to inmates at Monroe Correctional Complex: Medium Security Unit. Monroe, WA.
2016	August 13. "Languages of the World". University Beyond Bars, Public Lecture series to inmates at Monroe Correctional Complex: Minimum Security Unit Monroe, WA.
2016	May 7-8. "Seeing the Hidden Structure of Language". Paws on Science : Husky Wekeend. Pacific Science Center, Seattle, WA.
2014	Breaking Idioms with Right Node Raising. Syntax Roundtable. UW.
2014	If you teach a robot to talk Scholar's Studio: Robot Research at the Commons. UW. Seattle, WA.
2014	UW Canadian Studies Newsletter - Report about Linguistics Colloquium https://jsis.washington.edu/canada/outreach/focus.shtml#mallonlingcoll

Media Coverage

2014	UW Provost November Report - "Experience using Canvas classroom software as a TA for LING 233" http://www.washington.edu/trends/bringing-the-real-world-of-language-to-the-classroom
2013	LINGUIST List Blog - "TEDxEMU Presentation by LL Editor Brent Woo" http://blog.linguistlist.org/ll-main/tedxemu-presentation-by-brent-woo/

Nonacademic work

Sum 2014	Intern . Linguistic Society of America (LSA). Washington, DC.
2011–2013	Research Assistant. LINGUIST List. Ypsilanti, MI.

2013 "Say a Command". TEDxEMU. Ypsilanti, MI.

Languages

Native	English
Proficient	Russian, Thai
Basic	Finnish, Rusyn, Slovak, Hungarian, Mandarin, Sanskrit

Professional Memberships

2016–	UW Graduate and Professional Student Senate Elected Senator
2011–	Linguistic Society of America Program Committee, elected student member Committee for Ethnic Diversity in Linguistics, member
2013–	Slavic Linguistics Society Elected Webmaster (2016-2021)

References

Barbara Citko. Professor of Linguistics. UW.
Sharon Hargus. Professor of Linguistics. UW.
T. Daniel Seely. Professor of Linguistics. Eastern Michigan U.
Clarissa Surek-Clark. Lecturer of Linguistics. The Ohio State University.
(Teaching reference)